Mary Morris Scrapbooks
Connecticut Historical Society
Mary Morris Scrapbooks.
1873-1924
Connecticut Historical Society
Morris, Mary
Collection consists of clippings of obituaries and news of social events appearing in the Hartford Courant of Hartford, Connecticut and the Republican of Springfield, Massachusetts, chronologically arranged.
188 volumes
Biographical Sketch
Mary Pamelia was born in New York City on January 1, 1848, the daughter of Festus C. and Sarah (Lincoln) Felt. On May 15, 1867 she married John Emory Morris of the Travelers Insurance Company of Hartford, Connecticut. She was the mother of Henry Lincoln, Edward Bontecou and John Felt Morris. She died at her home at 66 Niles Street in Hartford on September 12, 1924.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of clippings of obituaries and news of social events appearing in the Hartford Courant of Hartford, Connecticut and the Republican of Springfield, Massachusetts.
Arrangement
Materials are organized into three series based on arrangement by the donor.
Series I: Obituary Scrapbooks consists of clippings of obituaries appearing in the Hartford Courant and the Springfield Republican.
Series II: Social Scrapbooks Collection consists of clippings of engagements, weddings, balls and other social events appearing in the Hartford Courant of Hartford, Connecticut and the Republican of Springfield, Massachusetts, chronologically arranged.
Indexes
Series III: Indexes to Obituary Scrapbooks Names are indexed by alphabet groupings, that is for example, all the A's are listed together in chronological order by date of death, but not in strict alphabetical sequence. Although Mrs. Morris continued clipping obituaries until almost the end of her life, her health was such that she did not feel up to indexing them after February of 1922.
Series IV: Indexes to Social Event Scrapbooks are indexed by alphabet groupings, that is for example, all the "A" surnames are listed together in chronological order by date of the social event, but not in strict alphabetical sequence. Although Mrs. Morris continued clipping social events until almost the end of her life, her health was such that she did not feel up to indexing them after November of 1921.
Materials are arranged chronologically within the first two series and in alphabetical groups as distinct from alphabetical order in the third series.
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the collection.
Accruals
The collection is closed.
Subject Headings
Corporate Names
Daniel Slote & Company
Subjects
Obituaries -- Connecticut -- Hartford; Obituaries -- Massachusetts -- Springfield; Thanksgiving Day; Trade-marks
Geographic Names
Hartford (Conn.) -- Social life and customs.
Contents:
- I. Obituary Scrapbooks
  - Obituaries, 1873 - January 1883 (Volume 1)
  - Obituaries, February 1883 - February 1884 (Volume 2)
  - Obituaries, February 1884 - January 1885 (Volume 3)
  - Obituaries, February 1885 - November 1885 (Volume 4)
  - Obituaries, December 1885 - August 1886 (Volume 5)
  - Obituaries, August 1886 - February 1887 (Volume 6)
  - Obituaries, February 1887 - August 1887 (Volume 7)
  - Obituaries, August 1887 - February 1888 (Volume 8)
  - Obituaries, February 1888 - July 1888 (Volume 9)
  - Obituaries, July 1888 - January 1889 (Volume 10)
  - Obituaries, January 1889 - June 1889 (Volume 11)
  - Obituaries, June 1889 - December 1889 (Volume 12)
  - Obituaries, December 1889 - May 1890 (Volume 13)
  - Obituaries, May 1890 - November 1890 (Volume 14)
  - Obituaries, November 1890 - February 1891 (Volume 15)
  - Obituaries, February 1891 - July 1891 (Volume 16)
  - Obituaries, July 1891 - February 1892 (Volume 17)
  - Obituaries, March 1892 - December 1892 (Volume 18)
  - Obituaries, December 1892 - May 1893 (Volume 19)
  - Obituaries, May 1893 - November 1893 (Volume 20)
  - Obituaries, December 1893 - May 1894 (Volume 21)
  - Obituaries, May 1894 - November 1894 (Volume 22)
  - Obituaries, November 1894 - March 1895 (Volume 23)
  - Obituaries, March 1895 - September 1895 (Volume 24)
  - Obituaries, September 1895 - February 1896 (Volume 25)
  - Obituaries, February 1896 - June 1896 (Volume 26)
  - Obituaries, June 1896 - November 1896 (Volume 27)
  - Obituaries, November 1896 - March 1897 (Volume 28)
  - Obituaries, March 1897 - July 1897 (Volume 29)
  - Obituaries, August 1897 - December 1897 (Volume 30)
  - Obituaries, December 1897 - May 1898 (Volume 31)
  - Obituaries, May 1898 - October 1898 (Volume 32)
  - Obituaries, October 1898 - January 1899 (Volume 33)
  - Obituaries, January 1899 - June 1899 (Volume 34)
  - Obituaries, June 1899 - September 1899 (Volume 35)
  - Obituaries, September 1899 - January 1900 (Volume 36)
  - Obituaries, January 1900 - March 1900 (Volume 37)
  - Obituaries, March 1900 - July 1900 (Volume 38)
  - Obituaries, July 1900 - October 1900 (Volume 39)
  - Obituaries, October 1900 - January 1901 (Volume 40)
  - Obituaries, January 1901 - April 1901 (Volume 41)
  - Obituaries, April 1901 - August 1901 (Volume 42)
  - Obituaries, August 1901 - December 1901 (Volume 43)
  - Obituaries, December 1901 - March 1902 (Volume 44)
  - Obituaries, March 1902 - June 1902 (Volume 45)
  - Obituaries, June 1902 - October 1902 (Volume 46)
  - Obituaries, October 1902 - January 1903 (Volume 47)
  - Obituaries, January 1903 - May 1903 (Volume 48)
  - Obituaries, May 1903 - September 1903 (Volume 49)
  - Obituaries, September 1903 - December 1903 (Volume 50)
  - Obituaries, December 1903 - February 1904 (Volume 51)
  - Obituaries, February 1904 - May 1904 (Volume 52)
  - Obituaries, May 1904 - August 1904 (Volume 53)
  - Obituaries, August 1904 - November 1904 (Volume 54)
  - Obituaries, November 1904 - February 1905 (Volume 55)
  - Obituaries, February 1905 - April 1905 (Volume 56)
  - Obituaries, April 1905 - July 1905 (Volume 57)
  - Obituaries, July 1905 - November 1905 (Volume 58)
  - Obituaries, November 1905 - February 1906 (Volume 59)
  - Obituaries, February 1906 - April 1906 (Volume 60)
  - Obituaries, April 1906 - July 1906 (Volume 61)
  - Obituaries, July 1906 - October 1906 (Volume 62)
  - Obituaries, October 1906 - January 1907 (Volume 63)
  - Obituaries, January 1907 - March 1907 (Volume 64)
  - Obituaries, March 1907 - June 1907 (Volume 65)
  - Obituaries, June 1907 - August 1907 (Volume 66)
  - Obituaries, August 1907 - November 1907 (Volume 67)
  - Obituaries, November 1907 - January 1908 (Volume 68)
  - Obituaries, January 1908 - March 1908 (Volume 69)
  - Obituaries, March 1908 - June 1908 (Volume 70)
  - Obituaries, June 1908 - September 1908 (Volume 71)
  - Obituaries, September 1908 - December 1908 (Volume 72)
  - Obituaries, December 1908 - March 1909 (Volume 73)
  - Obituaries, March 1909 - June 1909 (Volume 74)
  - Obituaries, June 1909 - December 1909 (Volume 75)
  - Obituaries, September 1909 - December 1909 (Volume 76)
  - Obituaries, December 1909 - March 1910 (Volume 77)
  - Obituaries, March 1910 - May 1910 (Volume 78)
  - Obituaries, May 1910 - August 1910 (Volume 79)
  - Obituaries, August 1910 - November 1910 (Volume 80)
  - Obituaries, November 1910 - February 1911 (Volume 81)
  - Obituaries, February 1911 - April 1911 (Volume 82)
  - Obituaries, April 1911 - July 1911 (Volume 83)
  - Obituaries, July 1911 - November 1911 (Volume 84)
  - Obituaries, November 1911 - February 1912 (Volume 85)
  - Obituaries, February 1912 - April 1912 (Volume 86)
  - Obituaries, April 1912 - August 1912 (Volume 87)
  - Obituaries, August 1912 - October 1912 (Volume 88)
  - Obituaries, October 1912 - March 1913 (Volume 89)
  - Obituaries, March 1913 - July 1913 (Volume 90)
  - Obituaries, July 1913 - October 1913 (Volume 91)
  - Obituaries, October 1913 - January 1914 (Volume 92)
  - Obituaries, January 1914 - April 1914 (Volume 93)
  - Obituaries, April 1914 - August 1914 (Volume 94)
  - Obituaries, August 1914 - December 1914 (Volume 95)
  - Obituaries, December 1914 - March 1915 (Volume 96)
  - Obituaries, March 1915 - May 1915 (Volume 97)
  - Obituaries, May 1915 - December 1915 (Volume 98)
  - Obituaries, September 1915 - November 1915 (Volume 99)
  - Obituaries, November 1915 - January 1916 (Volume 100)
  - Obituaries, January 1916 - April 1916 (Volume 101)
  - Obituaries, April 1916 - July 1916 (Volume 102)
  - Obituaries, July 1916 - November 1916 (Volume 103)
  - Obituaries, November 1916 - January 1917 (Volume 104)
  - Obituaries, January 1917 - March 1917 (Volume 105)
  - Obituaries, March 1917 - July 1917 (Volume 106)
  - Obituaries, July 1917 - November 1917 (Volume 107)
  - Obituaries, November 1917 - February 1918 (Volume 108)
  - Obituaries, February 1918 - May 1918 (Volume 109)
  - Obituaries, May 1918 - August 1918 (Volume 110)
  - Obituaries, August 1918 - December 1918 (Volume 111)
  - Obituaries, December 1918 - March 1919 (Volume 112)
  - Obituaries, March 1919 - August 1919 (Volume 113)
  - Obituaries, August 1919 - December 1919 (Volume 114)
  - Obituaries, December 1919 - March 1920 (Volume 115)
  - Obituaries, March 1920 - July 1920 (Volume 116)
  - Obituaries, July 1920 - October 1920 (Volume 117)
  - Obituaries, October 1920 - January 1921 (Volume 118)
  - Obituaries, January 1921 - April 1921 (Volume 119)
  - Obituaries, April 1921 - July 1921 (Volume 120)
  - Obituaries, July 1921 - October 1921 (Volume 121)
  - Obituaries, October 1921 - December 1921 (Volume 122)
  - Obituaries, December 1921 - February 1922 (Volume 123)
  - Obituaries, February 1922 - May 1922 (Volume 124)
  - Obituaries, May 1922 - July 1922 (Volume 125)
  - Obituaries, July 1922 - October 1922 (Volume 126)
  - Obituaries, October 1922 - December 1922 (Volume 127)
  - Obituaries, December 1922 - March 1923 (Volume 128)
  - Obituaries, March 1923 - May 1923 (Volume 129)
  - Obituaries, May 1923 - August 1923 (Volume 130)
  - Obituaries, August 1923 - October 1923 (Volume 131)
- II. Social Event Scrapbooks
  - Social Events, 1873 - 1882 (Volume S1)
  - Social Events, 1882 - 1885 (Volume S2)
  - Social Events, January 1886 - October 1889 (Volume S3)
  - Social Events, November 1889 - November 1891 (Volume S4)
  - Social Events, November 1891 - April 1894 (Volume S5)
  - Social Events, April 1894 - October 1895 (Volume S6)
  - Social Events, October 1895 - May 1896 (Volume S7)
  - Social Events, May 1896 - June 1897 (Volume S8)
  - Social Events, June 1897 - October 1898 (Volume S9)
  - Social Events, November 1898 - October 1899 (Volume S10)
  - Social Events, October 1899 - November 1900 (Volume S11)
  - Social Events, November 1900 - October 1901 (Volume S12)
  - Social Events, October 1901 - September 1902 (Volume S13)
  - Social Events, September 1902 - September 1903 (Volume S14)
  - Social Events, September 1903 - June 1904 (Volume S15)
  - Social Events, June 1904 - January 1905 (Volume S16)
  - Social Events, January 1905 - October 1905 (Volume S17)
  - Social Events, October 1905 - June 1906 (Volume S18)
  - Social Events, May 1906 - January 1907 (Volume S19)
  - Social Events, January 1907 - July 1907 (Volume S20)
  - Social Events, July 1907 - January 1908 (Volume S21)
  - Social Events, January 1908 - July 1908 (Volume S22)
  - Social Events, July 1908 - January 1909 (Volume S23)
  - Social Events, February 1909 - October 1909 (Volume S24)
  - Social Events, October 1909 - June 1910 (Volume S25)
  - Social Events, June 1910 - April 1911 (Volume S26)
  - Social Events, April 1911 - October 1911 (Volume S27)
  - Social Events, October 1911 - May 1912 (Volume S28)
  - Social Events, June 1912 - December 1912 (Volume S29)
  - Social Events, January 1913 - June 1913 (Volume S30)
  - Social Events, July 1913 - December 1913 (Volume S31)
  - Social Events, January 1914 - June 1914 (Volume S32)
  - Social Events, June 1914 - January 1915 (Volume S33)
  - Social Events, January 1915 - June 1915 (Volume S34)
  - Social Events, July 1915 - December 1915 (Volume S35)
  - Social Events, December 1915 - June 1916 (Volume S36)
  - Social Events, June 1916 - November 1916 (Volume S37)
  - Social Events, November 1916 - May 1917 (Volume S38)
  - Social Events, May 1917 - September 1917 (Volume S39)
  - Social Events, September 1917 - February 1918 (Volume S40)
  - Social Events, February 1918 - August 1918 (Volume S41)
  - Social Events, August 1918 - March 1919 (Volume S42)
  - Social Events, March 1919 - July 1919 (Volume S43)
  - Social Events, July 1919 - November 1919 (Volume S44)
  - Social Events, November 1919 - March 1920 (Volume S45)
  - Social Events, March 1920 - June 1920 (Volume S46)
  - Social Events, June 1920 - November 1920 (Volume S47)
  - Social Events, November 1920 - February 1921 (Volume S48)
  - Social Events, February 1921 - May 1921 (Volume S49)
  - Social Events, May 1921 - July 1921 (Volume S50)
  - Social Events, July 1921 - November 1921 (Volume S51)
  - Social Events, November 1921 - August 1924 (Volume S52)
- III. Indexes to Obituary Scrapbooks
  - Index to Obituary Scrapbooks, 1873-February 1896 (Volume I1)
  - Index to Obituary Scrapbooks, February 1896 - March 1919 (Volume I2)
  - Index to Obituary Scrapbooks, March 1919 - February 1922 (Volume I3)
- IV. Indexes to Social Event Scrapbooks
  - Index to Social Events Scrapbooks, 1878 - April 1911 (Volume SI1)
  - Index to Social Events Scrapbooks, April 1911 - November 1921 (Volume SI2)